Guide to the Margaret Wylie papers, 1926-1963.
Wylie, Margaret papers, 1926-1963.
- Series II. Subject Files, Correspondence,Booklets, and Questionnaires
  - 1936-1937
    - College of Home Economics - program plans, reports, guidelines (Miss Grace Henderson); "Toy Soldiers March" by Katherine Reeves, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Cornell Child Study Program - resources and course material, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with study clubs, county leaders, colleagues; In alphabetical order (1 of 2), 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 2 of 2, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence with Dr. Ruth Andrus, State Education Department, Albany, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence with Miss Grace Henderson, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Department of Family Life - objectives, program development, personnel, research, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Extension service documents - 4-H, articles, financial summary of counties, meetings, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Family Life Conference - Organization, materials, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Family Life Conference - Registration and attendance, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Family Life Conference - Questionnaires, feedback, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Family Life Extension study clubs - Older Youth (Entorf, Rockwood); Adult groups (Rockwood), 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Farm and Home Week program materials, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - "The Farmer's Wife" magazine, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Foods and Nutrition newsletters, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Home Bureau general information and statistics; questionnaires and statistical studies (tabulation), 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Household management study groups: "Overcoming Fatigue", 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Monthly newsletters to agents (Mrs. Small), 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Monthly newsletters to study clubs, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Monthly Report of Supervisors and Specialists/ Narrative Report (by Dr. Wylie) Family Life Department, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - National Kindergarten Association, 8 West 40th Street, New York City, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - New York State Fair Committee - exhibit rules, meeting minutes, correspondence, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Orientation in Family and Social Relationships, Family Life 113Syllabus, discussion, final exam; reference lists, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Parent education program, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Plans of work, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - "Points for Parents" - a playlet for Parent-Teacher Associations, child study groups, and mothers' clubs by Edyth Thomas Wallace, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Procedures folder, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Project reports from counties, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Programs: conferences, conventions and other meetings, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - Publicity: newspaper clippings regarding programs, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Radio programs: scripts and advertising bulletins, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - Requests for information regarding WPA Nursery School and Parent Education program, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 35)
    - Requests for work from county clubs, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - Summer Session - classes, correspondence, scholarships, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - Telegrams and long-distance calls, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - Trip reports, 1936-1937 (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - 1937-1938
    - Agendas: Extension, Family Life Department, Nursery School and Graduate Staff meetings, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - American Home Economics Association - Reports, articles, correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - American Youth Commission - "Programs for Rural Youth" outlines, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Association for Childhood Education, 45th Annual Convention, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Annual report, 1937 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Books purchased by the College of Home Economics, MVR Library, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Bulletins (course and program guides) from Cornell and elsewhere, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Calendar and program schedules; clinic schedules, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Campus discussion group: "Insurance", 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Collected health and household advice, clippings; news related to the college, extension and 4-H, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Conferences attended by Dr. Wylie, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, in alphabetical order, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence from Grace M. Henderson, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Curriculum revisions, Family Life 126, 107, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Dispute with Mr. Arthur Bartlett, American Magazine article featuring Jamestown twins, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Epsilon Sigma Phi - minutes, correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Extension Service - directories, events, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Extension Service Annual Conference, Mar. 23-25; Program, discussions, presentation material, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Family Life 114, 100 - Objectives, descriptions, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Family Life Conference, May 24-27 - Program, invitations, discussion outlines, blank forms, questionnaires, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Farm and Home Week, February 14-18, 1938 (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Films from the Departments of Agriculture and Home Economics - listing and descriptions, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - 4-H - letters from Dorothy DeLany, other materials, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Health bulletins, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Home Bureau materials; Annual Federation of Home Bureaus meeting minutes and correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Household management survey, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Magazine abstracts prepared for the use of government officials by the Division of Press Intelligence for the United States Government, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Missionaries - Cornell School; conferences, meetings, programsRural Missions Conference, 3rd annual, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 28)
    - Monthly newsletter to study clubs, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 29)
    - Monthly reports, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 30)
    - National Congress of Parents and Teachers - publications, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 31)
    - National Council of Parent Education - program information, correspondence, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 32)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - New York State Department of Education/ National Association for Nursery Education, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - New York State Department of Health, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - New York State Social Security Plans, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - Plans of Work, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - Procedures folder, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - Departmental affairs and memoranda, 1937-1938 (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - Plans of Work, State Extension Program, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Programs: conferences, conventions and other meetings, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Publications (lists and general information from miscellaneous sources), 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Health plays for school use - catalog, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Plans of work, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Publicity, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Reports, miscellaneous, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Red Cross (The American National Red Cross), 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Requests from counties, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Requests for 1937-1938, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Requests for misc. meetings, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Radio programs, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Report, annual, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Report, annual, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Statistical information from miscellaneous sources, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Stencils, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Summer school scholarship, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Toy exhibit, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Trip reports, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture - Correspondence, extension service circulars, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - U.S. Department of the Interior, Bureau of Education, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 31)
    - U.S. Department of Labor, 1937-1938 (Box 24, Folder 32)
  - 1938-1940
    - Questionnaire - A.H. Ec. research findings: "Special Researches Useful in Teaching Child Development, Parent Education and Family Life.' (Box 24, Folder 37)
    - Plans of work, 1938-1939 (Box 24, Folder 40)
    - Plans of work, 1939-1940 (Box 24, Folder 38)
    - Modus Operandi, 1939-1940 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - 4-H clubs: history and background, qualifications for leadership (Box 24, Folder 39)
    - Newspaper clippings (Box 24, Folder 41)
    - Radio (Box 24, Folder 42)
    - Comments for 1938 annual report, 1938 (Box 24, Folder 43)
    - Family Life Conference, 1939 (Box 24, Folder 44)
    - Family Life Conference report, May 23-26, 1939, 1939 (Box 26, Folder 66)
    - Family Life Conference: questionnaire on program (evaluation), 1940 (Box 24, Folder 45)
    - May Family Life Conference: summaries, 1940 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - May Family Life Conference: requests for exhibit materials, 1940 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - May Family Life Conference: materials used, 1940 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - May Family Life Conference: studio groups (data), 1940 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Reports, annual, 1939-1940 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Programs, 1939-1940 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Permissions, 1939-1940? (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Comments for 1939 annual report, 1939 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Report, annual, 1938-1939 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Reports, Family Life department, 1939-1940 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Family Life programs, other states, 1939-1940 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Reports, miscellaneous (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Reports, monthly (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Trip reports, Dr. Wylie (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Travel cards, 1939-1940 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Trip reports, 1939-1940 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous requests for Dr. Wylie's time (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Requests from counties, 1938-1939 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - County requests, Miss Hedrick, 1938-39 (Box 26, Folder 41)
    - Requests, Miss Hedrick, 1939-1940 (Box 26, Folder 42)
    - Miscellaneous requests, 1938-1939 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous requests for materials, 1938-1939 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous requests, 1939-1940 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous notices, 1939-1940 (Box 26, Folder 76)
    - Miscellaneous mimeographed material requested, 1939-1940 (Box 26, Folder 77)
    - Calendar and schedule, Mr. Entorf, 1939-1940 (Box 26, Folder 58)
    - Calendars, Mrs. Hedrick, 1939-1940 (Box 26, Folder 59)
    - Telegrams and telephone calls, 1939-1940 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Social Security Act, 1938-1939 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Special problems - correspondence on help given, 1939-1940 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - State Bureau of Child Development and Parent Education, 1939-1940 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Stencils, 1939-1940 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Study club information, 1938-1939 (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Study club letters, 1939-1940 (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Summer scholarship, 1939 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - SS E225b Seminar: "Seminar in Family Life with Special Consideration of the Adult in Relationships." (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - SS E116 Seminar: "Parent Education" (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Summer session, 1939 (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - U.S. Department of Commerce, 1938-1939 (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - U.S. Department of the Interior, 1938-1939 (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - U.S. Department of the Interior, 1939-1940 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - U.S. Department of Labor, 1939-1940 (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - U.S. Office of Education, 1939-1940 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - University of the State of New York, 1939-1940 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - White House conference: "Children in a Democracy", 1938-1939 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - White House conference: "Children in a Democracy" and conference of extension specialists which followed, 1939-1940 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Franking regulations, postage, 1939-1940 (Box 26, Folder 67)
  - 1940-1941
    - Attendance at nursery school tour (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Schedule, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Calendar and schedule, Mark L. Entorf, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Calendar and schedule, Mrs. Hedrick, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Defense Committee, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Family Life plays, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Films, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Franking privilege, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous mimeographed material requested, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Monthly reports, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Miscellaneous notices, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Modus Operandi, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - New York Academy of Medicine (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - New Jersey Radio, 1940 (Box 26, Folder 36)
    - Radio talks, 1939-1940 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Plans of Work, 1940 (Box 26, Folder 38)
    - Programs, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 39)
    - Requests for magazines for exhibit, Family Life Conference, 1941 (Box 26, Folder 43)
    - Speeches, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 45)
    - State Education Department, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 46)
    - Telegrams, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 47)
    - Trip reports, Mrs. Packer, 1941 (Box 26, Folder 48)
    - Trip reports, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 49)
    - University of the State of New York, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 50)
    - U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 51)
    - U.S. Department of the Interior, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 52)
    - Annotations, for library books, 1939-1941 (Box 26, Folder 54)
    - Campus activities (Box 26, Folder 60)
    - Civics - course by T.N. Hurd (Box 26, Folder 61)
    - Extension staff (Box 26, Folder 64)
    - Newsletter: Miss Ella Gardner, Recreation Specialist, USDA, 1930-1940 (Box 26, Folder 68)
    - Date regarding leaders (Box 26, Folder 74)
    - White House Conference, 1940 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Wisconsin Farm and Home Week, 1940 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - The Red Line from Moscow (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - 1950-1959
    - College of Home Economics Evaluation Steering Committee Meeting Minutes, 1955-1956 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Program Guides for Home Demonstration Work, 1950-1951 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Program Guides for Home Demonstration Work, 1951-1952 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Program Guides for Home Demonstration Work, 1952-1953 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Program Guides for Home Demonstration Work, 1953-1954 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - Program Guides for Home Demonstration Work, 1956-1957 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Program Guides for Home Demonstration Work, 1958-1959 (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Program Guides for Home Demonstration Work, 1959 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Midcentury White House Conference on Children and Youth, December 1950 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - New York State Attendees of White House Conference on Children and Youth, 1950 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Midcentury White House Conference on Children and Youth -Material on agencies and exhibits, 1950 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - USDA Extension Service-Follow-up to Midcentury White House Conference, 1951 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - 7 Radio Discs of Midcentury White House Conference on Children and Youth, 1950 (Box 39)